Rafael Luis Neves Amaro

contact@rafaelamaro.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafamaro

Summary

Passionate Software Engineer who works in innovation technology companies with a focus on mobility and user experience / interaction design. Six years experience in developing applications and systems with a focus on mobile and web applications. Extensive experience on the Web and Mobile platforms, from customization of the OS for specific contexts to applications for business. Agile methodologies, processes of development and design of products, such as SCRUM. Build projects from the architect stage product at companies focusing on technology. Passionate about clean code, clean architecture and software development and I am sure that it is more than just an engineering work. It is a form of art. This makes a software developer a little of a craftsman, engineer and scientist.

Skills

Personal

- Capable to multi-task and to obtain commitment to the organization's goals and strategic directions.
- Problem-solver mindset, doing whatever it takes to deliver optimal results within the given constraints, always analyzing the problem and seeking to make it an opportunity.
- Solid knowledge in computing, processes and software architect.
- Advanced English proficiency and Brazilian Portuguese as native language.

Methodologies and processes

- Agile practices
- Scrum
- Clean architecture

Technologies

I have been working mostly with .Net C#, iOS, Android, Java, Php and Javascript for the past 5 years, but I have knowledge in following areas:

- Languages: C#, Java, Php, Javascript, Swift, Objective-C
- Frameworks: .Net, Entity Framework, iOS SDK, Android SDK, Laravel, Zend,

JQuery

- Databases: Oracle, Sql Server, MySQL
- Internet Technologies: RESTful Web services and APIs
- Others: XML, JSON, HTML, CSS

Experience

Crmall - Sistema de Informação de Marketing - Full Stack Developer

Maringá, Paraná - 2015-2016

Responsible for development of apps mobile and web sites/services used in-house. One of a team of 4 developers involved in the full lifecycle of the product, from analysis and specification to development and support.

- Participated as a software engineer
- Helped to build a new mobile team applying software best practices
- Developed mobile applications with Android SDK
- Developed mobile applications with iOS SDK
- Developed back-end applications and APIs
- Oriented employees in the mindset of the company, that is, study problems in depth, have a critical opinion about a problem and choose the best solution available to solve

Crmall - Sistema de Informação de Marketing - .Net Software engineer

Maringá, Paraná – 2013-2015

Responsible for development of bespoke IT systems used in-house. One of a team of 6 developers involved in the full lifecycle of the product, from analysis and specification to development and support.

- Participated in the study and creation of CRM product
- Developed web application with Silverlight and DevExpress frameworks
- Developed back-end application and API using .Net framework

Benner Solutions - .Net Software engineer

Maringá, Paraná - 2010-2013

As a .Net Software engineer, I developed systems with focus on innovation in the areas of web to health system. Also participated in phases before the implementation like building of the product backlog with the product owner, user experience researching and prototyping.

- Developed applications, systems and operation system customizations to specific contexts in ASP.NET platform
 - Built product backlogs together with product owners
 - Applied reuse and design patterns techniques
- Developed and participated in the steps of researches and user experience processes analyzed and designed a system in Oracle 10g and Sql Server 2008 (frontend in Asp.Net Web Application) enabling the patient to create and manage their Personal Health Record (PHR). The solution features tools that support the monitoring aspects related to health and quality of life

Certification

Microsoft

070-480 Programming HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

Education

University of Maringá (Unicesumar)

2013 Post-graduate in Development of the applications with C#.

University of Cianorte (Unipar)

2009 Technologist degree in Analysis and Development of the Systems